准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
雪球效应
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
啊  看这巨大冰山多么雄伟壮丽
Ah, observe the majesty of the mighty iceberg
这冰冻的巨人
This frozen giant
一般漂浮在极地地区
normally found floating in polar regions
有时会漂流到较为温暖的水域
can sometimes stray into warmer waters
引发剧烈的气候变化
causing dramatic changes in climate
进而影响热带海洋生物
for tropical undersea life
裤头村
对  看来冬日老人昨晚来拜访我们了
Yes, it seems Old Man Winter
paid us a visit late last night
而他带来的既不是枕头也不是床单
and he brought with him not a pillow or a sheet
而是毯子
but a blanket
雪做的毯子
a blanket of snow
水母田
没错  从水母田
Yes, from Jellyfish Fields
到居民的住所
to residential abodes
停
再到繁忙的市中心
to bustling downtown
行
到处只有这种白白的东西
it's nothing but the white stuff
这也引起了本地居民的关注
And local residents are taking notice
海之霸
这是什么
What's this?
雨滴被冻成了冰晶
Drops of rain frozen into ice crystals?
我要利用它们的能量统治世界
I shall harness their energy and rule the world
住手
Stop
我要统治你们
I wish to rule you
雪地天使
Snow angel
我可谢谢你了  海绵宝宝
Thanks a lot, SpongeBob
你站在那吹口哨的时候
While you were just standing there whistling
有人拿雪球来扔我
someone threw a snowball at me
真的吗  派大星
Really, Patrick?
那雪球是长这样的吗
Did the snowball look like this?
是啊
Yeah
事态很严重  海绵宝宝
This is serious, SpongeBob
有人想抓我
Someone's after me
我应该得逃出裤头村
I think I better leave town
派大星  是我扔的
Patrick, I threw it
这是在打雪仗
We're having a snowball fight
懂不
Don't you get it?
打雪仗
Snowball fight?
我要玩
I want to play
那你得先做一个雪球
Well, first, you have to make a snowball
好啊
Oh, yeah
雪球
A snowball
这一定会特别棒
This is going to be great
什
Wha?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
能帮我做个雪球吗
Can you help me make a snowball?
行啊  兄弟
Sure, pal
谢了  兄弟
Thanks, buddy
派大星
Patrick
你怎么能这样
How could you?
这可是在打雪仗  忘了吗
It's a snowball fight, remember?
是没错
Oh, yeah
好啊
Yes
温暖火堆  舒服拖鞋
Warm fire, cozy slippers
还有热茶  再配上一片柠檬片
and a piping hot cup of tea with a lemon wedge
我这又是何苦呢
Why do I even bother?
你们两个能不能小点声
Would you two please keep it down?
章鱼哥
Squidward
你刚好能来加入我的军队
You're just in time to enlist in my army
加进来就能一起打败粉红威胁
Join me and together we'll defeat the Pink Menace
就是我
That's me
我可以先把你征为见习列兵
I can start you off as a buck private
不过只要你努力了
but with hard work
估计你就能升等
perhaps you can rise through the ranks
成普通列兵了
and become a regular private
谢谢你
Thanks
不过不用了  傻蛋少校
but no, thanks, Major Stupidity
你跟那边的胡扯将军
You and General Nonsense over there
自个儿打去  别拉上我
will have to fight without me
俩都骂到了
Got 'em both
派大星  你个笨蛋
Patrick, you fool
还没开始就结束了
This was over before it started
我认为你必须无条件投
I will now consider your unconditional surren
降
der
原来这就是他想要的结果
So, that's how he wants it to go down
你没打中我
You missed me
主队得一分
Score one for the boys back home
什么事
Yes?
派大星
Patrick
真是让我喜不起来的惊喜
What an unpleasant surprise
天啊  猜谜游戏可真是好玩啊
Oh, boy, nothing like a game of charades
我本来想跟你说我被雪呛到了
I was trying to tell you that I was choking on snow
可是雪就化成水了
but the snow melted and turned into water
然后我把水都喝了
and I drank all the water
现在我舒服了
now I'm better
好有意思
Fascinating
我刚干啥来着了
Now, where was I?
搞什么
What?
我能借你家厕所吗
Can I use your bathroom?
派大星  上你自己家厕所去
Patrick, go use your own bathroom
我憋不到那里
I don't think I can make it
能借吗
Please?
不能
No
能借吗
Please?
不能
No
能借吗
Please?
不能
No
能借吗
Please
那行  赶紧上
Okay, make it quick
没事了
That's okay
救助敌人
Aiding the enemy
我抓了你个正着  章鱼哥
I caught you red-handed, Squidward
海绵宝宝我跟你说  我只是
Look, SpongeBob, I was just
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
章鱼哥加我这边了
Squidward's on my side
我根本没有加
I most certainly am not
那就表示他支持我这边了
Then that means he's on my side
错了海绵宝宝  我也不是你那边的
No, SpongeBob, I'm not on your side either
我哪边的都不是
I'm on nobody's side
幼稚的小屁孩才打雪仗
Snowball fights are for immature children
我绝不会堕落到你们这种地步
and I will not stoop to your level
你们俩想用雪球互相把脑子砸出来
If you two want to knock
knock each other's brains out with snowballs
就请别把我扯进来
kindly leave me out of it
海绵宝宝  来把脑子砸出来吧
Come on, SpongeBob, let's go knock each other's brains out
我准备好了
I'm ready
派大星  脑子出来了
Okay, Patrick, it's out
这下有好戏看了
Now, there's something I'd actually like to see
直接坐前排应该没什么问题
Nothing wrong with getting a front-row seat, I suppose
什么鬼
What's this?
什
Wha
我
I
不对
No
你们这是在干什么
What are you doing?
你们应该是要互相把脑子打出来的
You're supposed to be knocking each other's brains out
我们签了和平条约  章鱼哥
We signed a peace treaty, Squidward
你说得对
You were right
小孩子才打仗
Fighting is for children
不对  我那时误导了你们
No, no, I misled you
大人也打仗
it's for adults, too
和平条约给我
Give me that peace treaty
好了
There
继续战争去吧
Let the war continue
章鱼哥  那不是和平条约
Squidward, that wasn't the peace treaty
是和平条约的复印件
That was a copy of the peace treaty
听好  你们两个太容易就放弃了
Look, you two are giving up too easily
派大星  假装我是海绵宝宝
Now, Patrick, pretend I'm SpongeBob
那我是谁
And who am I?
你是派大星
You're Patrick
我可以当蟹老板吗
Can I be Mr. Krabs?
不行
No
等等  为什么
Wait, why?
他是个好领导
He's a good leader
你能不能闭嘴
Would you butt out?
不能对蟹老板这么说话  章鱼哥
You can't talk to Mr. Krabs like that, Squidward
我是海绵宝宝
I'm SpongeBob
你是派大星
You're Patrick
现在你要做什么
Now, what are you going to do?
派大星  你为什么不扔海绵宝宝
Patrick, why didn't you hit SpongeBob?
你说你是海绵宝宝啊  海绵宝宝
You said you were SpongeBob, SpongeBob
没错  章鱼哥先生
It's true, Mr. Squidward
快回去工作
Now, get back to work
天啊
Oh, boy
我算是知道接下来会怎样了
All right, I can see where this is going
总而言之
Let's just say for all intents and purposes
我章鱼哥加入这场战争
that I, Squidward, am now part of this war
现在
Now
你都加入战争了  那你碉堡呢
If you're in this war, where's your fort?
我没碉堡  懂吗
I don't have one, okay?
现在
Now
得有座碉堡才行  章鱼哥
You gotta have a fort, Squidward
有碉堡才能取胜  章鱼哥
Forts win wars, Squidward
好  行
Okay, fine
你们要碉堡
You want a fort?
你们要的碉堡有了
There, there's your fort
现在
Now
那碉堡太小了  章鱼哥
That fort's too small, Squidward
没事的  派大星
It's okay, Patrick
这就只是个示范
It's just a demonstration
现在
Now
他说得对  章鱼哥
He's right, Squidward
那玩意保护不了你的
That thing would never protect you
小得可怜
It's downright puny
相信我  没事的
Trust me, it's fine
懂了吧
See?
它就是太小了
It is too small
我蹲下就没事了
Not if I crouch down
你们连个我蹲下的机会都不给
I mean, you didn't even give me a chance to crouch down
看见没
See?
我在这可以完美做到
Down here, I am perfectly
暴露目标
Exposed
你们两个能不能
Would you two please
不要再扔
stop throwing
雪球了
snowballs?
章鱼哥还击了
Squidward returned fire
开战了
Then it's war
不对不对  等下等下
No, no, wait, wait
我只是在做示范
I was just giving a demonstration
好了  都够了
All right, that's it
都是你们自找的
You guys asked for it
打中了
I got him
中你一脸  海绵宝宝
In your face, SpongeBob
还确实有点
That was actually kind of
刺激
exciting
我从来就没这么有活力过
Why, I've never felt so alive
他打中你了  海绵宝宝
He got you good, SpongeBob
隐蔽
Take cover
接招
Take that
打中了
I got you
接招
Take that
这回打中了
I got you that time
好耶
Oh, yeah
进攻
Incoming
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
什么事  派大星
Yes, Patrick?
章鱼哥现在好像打得很认真
I think Squidward's taking this really seriously
上一把雪球里面还有他竖笛
That last one had his clarinet in it
看来要实施B计划了
Looks like it's time for Plan B
怎么回事
What's going on?
没有雪球扔过来了
The snowballs have stopped falling
最好利用这段短暂的停火时间
I better take advantage of this momentary cease-fire
什么
What?
左侧暴露了
My left flank is exposed
那个胖海星会刚刚好打中我的
That bloated starfish is going to run right through me
我马上就补好
I'll just fix that right now
等等  这样北墙就成弱点了
Wait, that makes my north wall a weak spot
行了
Here we go
可要是他们从后面袭击  我就完蛋了
But if they attack from the rear, I'm a goner
好了
There
可是空袭要怎么办
But what about the possibility of an aerial attack?
这样应该就能成了
I guess that ought to do it
章鱼哥的碉堡现在几乎刀枪不入了
Fort Squidward is now all but impenetrable
那些傻子现在在哪
Now, where are those fools?
第一枪已经鸣响了
The first shot has been fired
接招  派大星
Take this, Patrick
尝尝我冰冻的怒火吧
Taste my frozen fury
胜利属于我
Victory is mine
我打中你们了
I got you now
听见什么了吗  派大星
Did you hear something, Patrick?
没有
Nope
蟹老板的垃圾
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
上品古董出售
啊  跳蚤市场
Ah, a yard sale
俗话说得好
You know the old saying
彼之垃圾  我之财宝
"One man's trash is another man's treasure"
一次性的
Disposable?
个屁
Phooey
对于蟹老板  一切垃圾都是财宝
For Mr. Krabs, all trash is treasure
清新剂
生意开张了
Open for business
淘到什么宝没
See anything you like?
我就花一块五买这把雨伞
Yeah, I'll give you $1.50 for this umbrella
才一块五
$1.50 for that?
可这是古董
But it's an antique
曾经属于一个女王
It belonged to a queen
要十块
Ten bucks
十块
Ten bucks?
可上面全是孔洞
It's full of holes
那女王是瑞士的
It was the queen of Switzerland
[ 瑞士奶酪多孔 ]
你说女王啊
A queen, you say?
真是
That's
等一下  瑞士没女王
Wait a second, they don't have a queen
那行  砍价老手
Okay, Mr. Bargain Hunter
五块钱
Five bucks
成交
Deal
全天候傻蛋的甜美香气啊
The sweet smell of an all-day sucker
超 大 棒 棒 糖
吃起来味道还更好
They taste even better
嗨  蟹老板
Hi, Mr. Krabs
你在干什么
What you doing?
我在卖古董
I'm having an antique sale
到处来看看吧
Have a look around
派大星  快看这玩意
Hey, Patrick, look at this thing
是不是好酷
Pretty cool, huh?
看着好像我昨天扔掉的马桶塞
That looks like the toilet plunger
I threw out yesterday
这可不是马桶塞
That ain't no toilet plunger
是个古董
This here's an antique
是
It, uh
17世纪的汤勺  你看
a 17th-century soup ladle, see?
我原来用法不对吗
Man, was I using mine wrong
多少钱
How much?
五块
Five bucks
我就只有七块
I've only got seven
成交
Deal
派大星  你这买家可真聪明
Patrick Star, you are one smart shopper
看看这酷毙了的汽水帽啊
Look at this neat-o soda-drinking hat
它曾经肯定属于一个第一名
It must've belonged to someone who was number one
有史以来  第一名都是屈指可数的
There's only been a handful of number ones
in the entire history of forever
说得对  海绵宝宝
That's right, SpongeBob
而你就是其中之一
and you're one of 'em
真的吗
Really?
这个帽子上写
This hat says
我是第一名
"Hey, I'm number one
我让重力来帮我喝饮料
and I let gravity do my drinking"
这顶帽子就是为你打造的  小子
This hat was made for you, boy
你天生就是戴这顶帽子的料
You were born to wear this hat
是不是很合身  小子
A perfect fit, eh, son?
谢谢蟹老板
Thank you, Mr. Krabs
谢谢你把我们带到了一起
Thank you for bringing us together
我要怎么报答你
How can I ever repay you?
付十块钱
With ten dollars
我就只有五块
All I have is five
那怕是不能成交了
Well, I guess it's no deal
我去去就回
I'll be right back
蟹老板  我找到了六毛八
Mr. Krabs, I found 68 cents
不过也许剩下的四块三毛二
But maybe you could take the other $4.32
可以从我工资扣
out of my paycheck
怎么样
What do you say?
那个
Well
不好说
I don't know
那行
Okay
只是看在你戴着帽子还挺帅的份上
But only 'cause you look so dashing in that hat
谢谢蟹老板
Thanks, Mr. Krabs
不用谢  小子
Don't mention it, boys
真是俩土包子
What a couple of rubes
不好意思  先生
Excuse me, sir
请问你是不是这家珍品摊的承办商
but are you the purveyor of this curio stand?
没错  正是
Yes, I am
听说你在卖这顶稀有的新奇汽水帽
I understand you're selling
this rare novelty drink hat
汽水帽
刚刚卖掉了
Fresh out
听我解释
Let me explain
我本来要用五百块找你买那顶汽水帽
I'm prepared to give you $500 for that drink hat
五五五五五
Fi-fi-fi-fi-fi
想得美
Not so fast
我要出一千块换帽子
I'll give you $1,000 for such a hat
我出十万现金换你说的帽子
I'll give you $100,000 in cash for said hat
先生  我要用一百万买下那顶帽子
Sir, I'll give you a million dollars for that hat
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
他在那  戴着我那值一百万的帽子
There he is with me million-dollar hat
必须趁早拿回来
I got to get it back
不然他就会发现帽子有多值钱了
before he finds out how much it's worth
泡泡的吹出量翻两倍了
My bubble production has increased twofold
多亏了你  帽帽
Thanks to you, Hatty
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
蟹老板
Hey, Mr. K
你古董卖的怎么样了
How's the antique biz treating you?
那个不用管
Never mind that
听好
Listen
我不想在派大星面前说
I didn't want to say this in front of Patrick
这帽子让你看起来像个女的
That hat makes you look like a girl
是漂亮妹子吗
Am I a pretty girl?
那个
Well, um
你
You're
你美若天仙
you're beautiful
行了  把帽子还给我
All right, now give me the hat back
可是蟹老板  你亲口说的
But, Mr. Krabs, you said it yourself
我天生就是戴这顶帽子的料
I was born to wear this hat
我不想还回去
I don't want to give it back
这顶帽子不能离我而去
I can't part with this hat now
毕竟我们一同经历了这么多
Not after all we've been through
谢谢  蟹老板
Thanks, Mr. Krabs
我要叫你帽帽
I'll call you Hatty
这时候你就出现了
And that's when you showed up
算了吧
Forget it
并且你也没有美若天仙
And you're not beautiful either
我没吗
I'm not?
帽子
海绵宝宝  我正要找你呢
SpongeBob, just the man I wanted to see
是不是还在玩那顶破烂旧帽子啊
Still playing with that dumb old hat, eh?
对
Yep
那顶无聊的旧帽子还没玩腻啊
Not sick of that boring old hat yet?
没错
Nope
对那垃圾一点都不厌烦吗
Not tired of that old piece of junk?
一丁点都没有吗
Not even a teensy, tiny bit?
没错
Nope
那你就应该不想看我袋子里的东西了
Then I guess you don't want to see what's in my bag
帽子
什么东西
What is it?
新奇古怪帽子
Novelty hats
这个带空调的怎么样
How about this air-conditioned one?
好像有点危险
Seems a little dangerous
带榨汁机的
The Juicer?
狐媚老大爷
Foxy Grandpa?
那你觉得如何
So, what do you say?
用你的笨帽子换这些帽子
Your silly hat for all these hats
不成交  蟹老板
No deal, Mr. Krabs
我要跟帽帽一起
I'm sticking with Hatty
不过还是谢谢你的好意
Thanks for the offer, though
还以为狐媚老大爷肯定可以引他上钩
I thought the Foxy Grandpa would get him for sure
我本来不想这样的
I didn't want to have to do this
但已经没有其他选择了
but he leaves me no other option
必须要使出惊吓手段
I'm going to have to scare it off of him
这样就能吓到他了
This'll scare him
我的老天爷啊
Oh, my gosh
奶
蛋
酪
有浮空的购物单
A floating shopping list
我不是购物单
I'm not a shopping list
我是鬼
I'm a ghost
听好了  海绵宝宝
Now, listen, SpongeBob
你怎么知道我名字的
How do you know my name?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是汽水帽之魂
I am the Ghost of Soda Drink Hats
我来这告诉你
And I'm here to tell you
你拥有的那顶汽水帽被诅咒了
that that soda drink hat you possess is cursed
诅咒
Cursed?
没错
Yes
它的原主现在已经故去了
It once belonged to some guy who's dead now
原主是谁
What guy?
史密提某某
Smitty something
史密提什么
Smitty what?
史密提
Smitty
沃本
Werben
耶格曼
Jaegerman
詹森
Jensen
他以前肯定是第一名
He must have been number one
鬼怪世界的第一名
Number one in Bogeyland
听好
Now, listen
马上会有诅咒降临到你身上
a curse will descend on you
但只要马上把帽子还回去就没事了
unless the hat is returned to its owner immediately
马上吗
Immediately?
马上
Immediately
还给主人
To its owner?
没错
Yes
现在吗
Right now?
对  对
Yes, yes
必须马上还给它的主人
It must be returned to its owner right now
蟹老板好
Hey, Mr. Krabs
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
我刚去让那顶被诅咒的汽水帽
I was returning the cursed soda drink hat
物归原主
to its original owner
史密提沃本耶格曼詹森
Smitty Werben Jaegerman Jensen
什么
What?
根本就没有史密提沃本耶格曼詹森
There is no Smitty Werben Jaegerman Jensen
真的有他
Sure there is
他就埋在浮尸公墓里
He's buried out in Floater's Cemetery
怎么会
How did?
我只
I just
你就
You did
我本来
I would
铲子给我
Give me that shovel
那是他的帽子  蟹老板
It was his hat Mr. Krabs
他是第一名
He was number one
冷静下来  蟹老板
Hold yourself together, Krabs
就只是个墓地
It's just a boneyard
到处是尸骨
filled with bones
什么声音
What's that?
是章鱼哥
It's Squidward
他来干什么
What's he doing here?
这里埋葬着章鱼哥的希望与梦想
"Here lie Squidward's hopes and dreams"
真是幼稚
What a baby
我到哪了
Where was I?
啊对
Oh, yeah
要找史密提那什么詹森
Gotta find Smitty Whatsajipster
老咸长眠于此
逝者安息
没有
Nope
逝者安息
潜水丹
没有
nope
傻子
没有
no
我旁边的是傻子
没有
no
No
没有
no
不在那边
nope, not there
整块墓园里的坟全都找遍了
I've checked every headstone in this cemetery
根本就没埋什么史密提沃吧啦吧啦
and there's no Smitty Wabbablabba buried here
快想想
Think, Krabs
也许海绵宝宝的话里有什么线索
Maybe something SpongeBob said
will give you some kind of clue
别忘了  舔门把手在外星球犯法
Remember, licking doorknobs
is illegal on other planets
不是这句
No, not that
你绝对猜不中
You'll never guess
我昨晚在我袜子里发现了什么
what I found in my sock last night
快去猜猜吧
Go ahead, guess
不对
No
那是他的帽子  蟹老板
It was his hat, Mr. Krabs
他是第一名
He was number one
真见鬼
Barnacles
我肯定找不到
I'll never find
史密提沃本
曼詹森
他家的坟
The grave
我不会真的要为了钱刨他坟吧
Am I really going to defile this grave for money?
当然要了
Of course I am
中奖了
Jackpot
好漂亮
It's beautiful
快到爸爸这来
Come to Papa
斯密提  放下
Come on, Smitty, let go
碎碎平安  斯密提
Rest in pieces, Smitty
值一百万的帽子归我了
I got the million-dollar hat
老兄  那是我的帽子
Hey, man, that's my hat
快还回来
Give it back
什么
What?
不行
No way
爬回你的坑里去  烂骨头
Just crawl back into your hole, bone boy
快点装死
Go ahead, play dead
看来只能从你身上硬抢了
I guess I'm going to have to take it from you
啊对对对
Yeah, right
就你一个能拿我怎么样
You and what army?
还有一大伙活死鬼
Only the army of the living dead
不好
Oh, no
我在深夜档的节目里看过
I've seen this on the late show
你们这些恶鬼要压制住我
You ghoulish fiends hold me down
轮流咬我的内脏
and take turns nibbling on my innards
然后吃掉我脑子  躯干都留给秃鹰
Then you eat my brain and leave my body for the buzzards
太恶心了
That's disgusting
咱只是想把帽子拿回来而已
We just want the hat back
想都别想
No flipping way
后退
Back up
我说后退
Back up, I say
进攻
Attack
发现目标
Tallyho
快看我  我演侠盗罗宾汉
Look at me, I'm Errol Fin
你们要散架了  骨头脑袋
You're falling apart, marrow brain
开什么玩笑
You must be kidding
回去洗洗睡吧
Back to oblivion
你们姐妹怎么样了
How's your sister?
骨头脑袋  游戏时间结束了
All right, boneheads, playtime's over
一百万
A million dollars
一百万到手了
I've got a million dollars
你们在这啊
There you are
总算到手了
Well, I got it
这种稀有的新奇古怪汽水帽
The rare novelty soda drink hat
一百万起拍吧
Let's start the bidding at $1 million
你这是狮子大开口吧
Yeah, you want that all at once?
一百万
A million dollars
你怕是逗死我了
You got to be kidding
那可怜的笨蛋没在逗你们
The poor sap's not kidding
没听说过吗
Didn't you hear?
有人发现了满满一仓库的帽子
They found a whole warehouse full of them
都不值钱了
They're worthless
垃圾
来给蟹老板掌声鼓励吧
Let's give Mr. Krabs a big hand
现在那个才值一百万
Now, that's worth a million dollars
孩子  别走
Hey, kid, wait up
是我先看到他的
I saw him first
我要给你十亿
I'll give you $1 billion
太让我心伤了
Well, that's a spirit breaker
真是幼稚
What a baby